<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Laure Zanna, U. of Oxford</title>
    <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Laure Zanna, U. of Oxford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Laure Zanna</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/climtechange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/climtechange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The oceans are a major sink of heat and carbon, able to delay climate
change. The role of ocean heat uptake remains central in quantifying
both the magnitude and timescale of the local and global climate
response to forcing. One main focus of our work is on the mechanisms
of heat and carbon storage and transport, and on the quantification of
their feedbacks onto the atmosphere and global climate. One goal is to
understand the role of air-sea fluxes and of the large-scale ocean
circulation in setting the ocean and atmospheric CO2 levels (The
figure shows timeseries of partial pressure of CO2 in the atmosphere,
North Altantic Ocean and Southern Ocean in response to wind forcing
from a numerical simulation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current and Past Funding on this topic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; NERC, UK FAFMIP: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FR000727%2F1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FR000727%2F1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; NERC, TICTOC: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FP019218%2F1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FP019218%2F1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/machinelearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/machinelearning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Big data is ubiquitious in many areas of science - we have recently
used a range of machine-learning algorihtms to tackle problems
in climate such as forecasting using neural networks, or
parametrization using super-resolution imaging. Stay tuned for more
projects and details soon&amp;hellip; or be in touch if you are interested in
collaborating with us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictability</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/predictability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/predictability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate projections are subject to three sources of uncertainties:
initial condition, model and scenario. Our research is concerned with
the first two kinds of errors. Specifically, how do the lack of ocean
observations, the chaotic nature of the climate system and the poor
representation of subgrid turbulent processes impact predictions on
intra-seasonal to centennial timescales. Being able to quantify the
predictability limits of the ocean is crucial for providing reliable
climate predictions. We use theory, observations and numerical
simulations to assess the uncertainties associated the ocean dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current and past funding on this topic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; NERC, Representing uncertainties:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FJ00586X%2F1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FJ00586X%2F1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turbulence</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/turbulence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/turbulence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ocean mesoscale eddies strongly affect the strength and variability of
ocean jets such as the Gulf Stream. The spatial scales of eddies are
too small to be resolved in climate models and hence their effects on
the large-scale circulation need to be parametrized. The most common
parametrizations used in coarse-resolution models are not adequate for
the current generation of models, in which eddies are partially
resolved. Furthermore, eddies are turbulent and stochastic in nature
however current bulk parametrizations of mesoscale eddies are
deterministic and do not account for subgrid transport fluctuations or
upscale turbulent cascades therefore leading to model error in the
representation of present and future climate change. The group is
developing new parametrizations which specifically account for such
effects and for model error associated with the uncertainty in the
parametrizations. The parametrizations are constructed by using first
principles, statistical mechanics, and high-resolution model outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current and Past Funding on this topic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; NERC, Modelling the ocean with random number: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FK013548%2F1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FK013548%2F1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Royal Society, International Exchanges Scheme,  Quantifying the Variability of Tracer Transport across the Gulf Stream&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variability</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/variability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/project/variability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In addition to its role played in heat and carbon uptake, the
large-scale ocean circulation in the Atlantic is an important driver
of European climate variability on interannual and decadal
timescales. Yet, the importance of its influence remains unclear due
in part to the short historical record and the poor representation of
this variability in climate simulations. To explore the large
discrepancies between coupled general circulation models (GCMs) in
their representation of the meridional overturning circulation (MOC)
decadal variability and predictions in the Atlantic sector, we have
introduced new diagnostic and numerical tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current and Past funding on this topic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; NERC, SummerTIME: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FM005887%2F1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FM005887%2F1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Royal Society, International Exchanges Scheme,  Quantifying the Variability of Tracer Transport across the Gulf Stream&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
