<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Laure Zanna, Oxford</title>
    <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Laure Zanna, Oxford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Laure Zanna</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/publication/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Global reconstruction of historical ocean heat storage and transport</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/zanna-et-al-2017b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/zanna-et-al-2017b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this work, we attempt to 1) extend global estimates of ocean
warming before 1950s; 2) infer how changes in ocean circulation can
shape patterns of ocean warming and sea level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We created a model based on a technique which maps information between
the surface of the ocean and its interior. The model is informed by a
combination of observations and computer simulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our findings suggest that 1) the ocean has gained energy equivalent to
roughly 436 $\times$ 10$^{21}$ Joules from 1871 to present, and that
2) changes in ocean processes (currents + mixing) have occured in the
past 60 yrs affecting regional sea level rise in the Atlantic Oceean.
While we have identified changes in ocean tranport in the past 60
years, we cannot directly attribute the changes to natural variability
or externally-forced climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our method is obviously subject to uncertainty from many different
sources (described in detail in the manuscript). However our results
are consistent with direct interior temperature measurements giving us
some confidence in the method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much work remains to be done to understand observed and predicted
patterns of oceaen warming and thermosteric sea level rise, which our
method can hopefully help address.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications of Deep Learning to Ocean Data Inference and Sub-Grid Parameterisation</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bolton-zanna-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bolton-zanna-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oceanographic observations are limited by sampling rates, while ocean models are limited by finite resolution and high viscosity and diffusion coefficients. Therefore both data from observations and ocean models lack information at small- and fast-scales.
Methods are needed to either extract information, extrapolate, or up-scale existing oceanographic datasets, to account for or represent unresolved physical processes.
Here we use machine learning to leverage observations and model data by predicting unresolved turbulent processes and sub-surface flow fields.
As a proof-of-concept, we train convolutional neural networks on degraded-data from a high-resolution quasi-geostrophic ocean model.
We demonstrate that convolutional neural networks successfully replicate the spatio-temporal variability of the sub-grid eddy momentum forcing, are capable of generalising to a range of dynamical behaviours, and can be forced to respect global momentum conservation.
The training data of our convolutional neural networks can be sub-sampled to 10-20\% of the original size without a significant decreasein accuracy.
We also show that the sub-surface flow field can be predicted using only information at the surface (e.g., using only satellite altimetry data).
Our study indicates that data-driven approaches can be exploited to predict both sub-grid and large-scale processes, while respecting physical principles, even when data is limited to a particular region or external forcing.
Our in-depth study presents evidence for the successful design of ocean eddy parameterisations for implementation in coarse-resolution climate models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean Obs&#39; 2019: Towards comprehensive observing and modeling systems for monitoring and predicting regional to coastal sea level</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/ponte-et-al-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/ponte-et-al-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate model uncertainty and trend detection of regional sea level projections in the open ocean and coastal zone</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/carson-et-al-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/carson-et-al-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergence of an anthropogenic signal in the North Atlantic warming hole</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/chemke-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/chemke-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future ocean climate change amplified and mitigated by circulation changes</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bronselaer-zanna-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bronselaer-zanna-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictability of North Atlantic Sea Surface Height</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/fraser-et-al-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/fraser-et-al-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The signature of oceanic processes on extratropical decadal SST anomalies</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/oreilly-zanna-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/oreilly-zanna-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The relationship between decadal sea surface temperature (SST) and
turbulent heat fluxes is assessed and used to identify where oceanic
processes play an important role in extratropical decadal SST
variability. In observational data sets and coupled climate model
simulations from the Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 5
archive, positive correlations between upward turbulent heat flux and
SSTs indicate an active role of oceanic processes over regions in the
North Atlantic, Northwest Pacific, Southern Pacific, and Southern
Atlantic. The contrasting nature of oceanic influence on decadal SST
anomalies in the Northwest Pacific and North Atlantic is
identified. Over the Northwest Pacific, SST anomalies are consistent
with changes in the horizontal wind-driven gyre circulation on
timescales of between 3 and 7 years, in both the observations and
models. Over the North Atlantic, SST anomalies are also preceded by
atmospheric circulation anomalies, though the response is stronger at
longer timescales—peaking at around 20 years in the observations and
at around 10 years in the models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eddy-mixing entropy and its maximization in forced-dissipative geostrophic turbulence</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/david-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/david-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote and local influences in forecasting Pacific SST: a linear inverse model and a multimodel ensemble study</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/dias-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/dias-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal to annual ocean forecasting skill and the role of model and observational uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/juricke-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/juricke-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of tropical precipitation on summertime Euro-Atlantic circulation via a circumglobal wave-train</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/oreilly-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/oreilly-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty and Scale Interactions in Ocean Ensembles: From Seasonal Forecasts to Multi-Decadal Climate Predictions</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/zanna-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/zanna-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The relationship between a deformation-based eddy parametrization and the LANS-alpha turbulence model</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bachman-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bachman-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southern Ocean carbon-wind stress feedback</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bronselaer-et-al-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bronselaer-et-al-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
