<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Laure Zanna, U. of Oxford</title>
    <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Laure Zanna, U. of Oxford</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Laure Zanna</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/publication/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Global reconstruction of historical ocean heat storage and transport</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/zanna-et-al-2017b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/zanna-et-al-2017b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of the excess energy stored in the climate system due
to anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions has been taken up by the
oceans, leading to thermal expansion and sea level rise.  The oceans
thus have an important role in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s energy imbalance.
Observational constraints on future anthropogenic warming critically
depend on accurate estimates of past ocean heat content (OHC)
change. We present a novel reconstruction of OHC since 1871, with
global coverage of the full ocean depth. Our estimates combine
timeseries of observed sea surface temperatures, with much longer
historical coverage than those in the ocean interior, together with a
representation (a Green&amp;rsquo;s function) of time-independent ocean
transport processes.  For 1955-2017, our estimates are comparable to
direct estimates made by infilling the available 3D time-dependent
ocean temperature observations. We find that the global ocean absorbed
heat during this period at a rate of 0.30 $\pm$ 0.06 W/m$^2$ in the
upper 2000 m and 0.028 $\pm$ 0.026 W/m$^2$ below 2000 m, with large
decadal fluctuations. The total OHC change since 1871 is estimated at
436 $\pm$91 $\times$ 10$^{21}$ J, with an increase during 1921-1946
(145 $\pm$ 62$\times$ 10$^{21}$ J) that is as large as during
1990-2015. By comparing with direct estimates, we also infer that,
during 1955-2017, up to half of the Atlantic Ocean warming and
thermosteric sea level rise at low-to-mid latitudes emerged due to
heat convergence from changes in ocean transport.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications of Deep Learning to Ocean Data Inference and Sub-Grid Parameterisation</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bolton-zanna-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bolton-zanna-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oceanographic observations are limited by sampling rates,
while ocean models are limited by finite resolution and high viscosity
and diffusion coefficients. Therefore both data from observations and
ocean models lack information at small-scales. Methods are needed to
either extract information, extrapolate, or up-scale existing
oceanographic datasets, to account for the unresolved physical
processes. Here we use machine learning to leverage observations and
model data by predicting unresolved turbulent processes and
sub-surface flow fields. As a proof-of-concept, we train convolutional
neural networks on degraded-data from a high-resolution
quasi-geostrophic ocean model. We demonstrate that convolutional
neural networks successfully replicate the spatio-temporal variability
of the sub-grid eddy momentum forcing, are capable of generalising to
a range of dynamical behaviours, and can be forced to respect global
momentum conservation. The training data of our convolutional neural
networks can be sub-sampled to 10-20% of the original size without a
significant increase in accuracy. We also show that the sub-surface
flow field can be predicted using only information at the surface,
mimicing when only satellite altimetry data is available. Our study
indicates that data-driven approaches can be exploited while
respecting physical principles, even when data is limited to a
particular region or external forcing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future ocean climate change amplified and mitigated by circulation changes</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bronselaer-zanna-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bronselaer-zanna-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The signature of oceanic processes on extratropical decadal SST anomalies</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/oreilly-zanna-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/oreilly-zanna-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The relationship between decadal sea surface temperature (SST) and
turbulent heat fluxes is assessed and used to identify where oceanic
processes play an important role in extratropical decadal SST
variability. In observational data sets and coupled climate model
simulations from the Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 5
archive, positive correlations between upward turbulent heat flux and
SSTs indicate an active role of oceanic processes over regions in the
North Atlantic, Northwest Pacific, Southern Pacific, and Southern
Atlantic. The contrasting nature of oceanic influence on decadal SST
anomalies in the Northwest Pacific and North Atlantic is
identified. Over the Northwest Pacific, SST anomalies are consistent
with changes in the horizontal wind-driven gyre circulation on
timescales of between 3 and 7 years, in both the observations and
models. Over the North Atlantic, SST anomalies are also preceded by
atmospheric circulation anomalies, though the response is stronger at
longer timescales—peaking at around 20 years in the observations and
at around 10 years in the models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eddy-mixing entropy and its maximization in forced-dissipative geostrophic turbulence</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/david-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/david-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote and local influences in forecasting Pacific SST: a linear inverse model and a multimodel ensemble study</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/dias-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/dias-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal to annual ocean forecasting skill and the role of model and observational uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/juricke-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/juricke-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of tropical precipitation on summertime Euro-Atlantic circulation via a circumglobal wave-train</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/oreilly-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/oreilly-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty and Scale Interactions in Ocean Ensembles: From Seasonal Forecasts to Multi-Decadal Climate Predictions</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/zanna-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/zanna-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The relationship between a deformation-based eddy parametrization and the LANS-alpha turbulence model</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bachman-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bachman-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergence of an anthropogenic signal in the North Atlantic warming hole</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/chemke-et-al-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/chemke-et-al-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southern Ocean carbon-wind stress feedback</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bronselaer-et-al-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/bronselaer-et-al-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> The dynamical and thermodynamical influences of the Atlantic Multidecadal Oscillation on continental climate</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/oreilly-et-al-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/oreilly-et-al-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Horizontal Resolution on Energy Transfers in Global Ocean Models</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/kjellsson-zanna-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/kjellsson-zanna-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic perturbations to sub-grid scale ocean mixing: Impacts on low frequency variability</title>
      <link>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/juricke-et-al-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaureZanna.github.io/publication/juricke-et-al-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
